# PAM BUTLER

# DATA ANALYST / BUSINESS ANALYST

# CONTACT



knitter.pam@gmail.com





linkedin.com/in/butler-pam



github.com/knitterpam

### ABOUT ME

I am a creative analyst who loves bringing data and visualization together to best communicate solutions to a wide audience. I enjoy using my wide range of experience to provide both left- and rightbrain options to business applications. I explore data to add factual value and informed decision-making to an employer.

# **SKILLS**

Data Analysis, SQL, Python, Tableau, Power BI, Excel (Pivot Tables, Vlookup), Remote Work/ **Communication, Documentation** 

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Nashville Software School Data Analytics Bootcamp**

March - June 2020 Nashville, TN

#### Valparaiso University

Valparaiso, IN B.B.A./Finance

Self-study courses Data Camp, Udemy, Pluralsight: SQL, Python, Excel, Data Visualization

# DATA ANALYTICS EXPERIENCE

#### Nashville Software School (Current)

Junior Data Analyst | March 2020 - June 2020

Completed a 4-month intensive Data Analyst program covering skills in Python, PostgreSQL, Tableau, Power Bl, Excel, GitHub, Agile/Kanban process, team and individual projects, and remote work, study, and presentation abilities. Gained hands-on experience applying skills by working with real-world data provided by local companies in a variety of fields, such as the United Nations (GDP and internet usage data), Nashville Metro Parks (geospatial location data), and the Nashville Historical Commission (City cemetery data).

#### **PROJECTS**

#### Capstone Project - U.S. Legal Permanent Resident (LPR) Analysis

 Acquired, cleaned, and analyzed government data using Excel, Python, and Tableau to examine trends in LPR entry, migration, and location over last decade

#### **Healthcare Bluebook Price Comparison Analysis**

 Analyzed pricing by facilities within a particular location (CBSA) by surgical code using Python and Tableau to create dashboard to aid company or users in decision-making

#### **United Nations GDP and Internet Usage Analysis**

 Analyzed GDP and internet usage using Python to see whether there was a correlation by creating queries, slices, and sorting on geodataframes, with added visualization

#### **Nashville City Cemetery Analysis**

Developed a data-based marketing brochure for the Nashville Historical Commission using Excel to identify factors for NHC to create future tour interest

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### **National Capitol Contracting, LLC**

Remote Transcriber | November 2013 - present

- Current security clearance with US Department of Justice
- Remotely, timely, and accurately transcribed sensitive government documents using Google Docs and Record Player transcription software, receiving consistent high ratings

#### **Tennessee State Fair Association**

#### **Creative Arts Department Superintendent** | May 2012 - December 2016

- Analyzed ticket and headcount after each annual Fair, contributing to overall 10% higher Fair attendance and increased Creative Arts entries each year
- Updated and contributed to digitization of entire Creative Arts catalog, and QA tested new online entry and judging processes
- Recruited new department heads within Creative Arts when required and coordinated with them to help develop advertising strategies, and increase volunteer participation
- Added demonstrations, musicians, and name-brand sponsored contests to further increase traffic to Creative Arts building

#### Angel Hair Yarn Co.

Co-owner, Manager | November 1994 - December 2008

- Performed market research and created advertising initiatives to drive sales and grow the business consistently throughout the store's lifespan
- Evaluated store data to manage inventory mix of up to \$100,000 and sales of nearly \$225,000 at business peak
- Trained employees, taught classes, created technical materials, and helped customers troubleshoot issues to increase repeat visits and sales

#### **HCA Healthcare Corp.**

# IT&S Customer Support and Training | October 1993 - February 2003

- Provided on-location hospital business office training for HCA products to back up files and access/update Medicaid/Medicare systems
- Utilized accounting system knowledge to become Tier 1 subject-matter expert for inhouse customer support of HCA-based Patient Accounting and Collections systems
- Interfaced with customers and Tier 3 developers to troubleshoot system issues
  - Created reference and training documents and mentoring for new support personnel resulting in easier onboarding process and increased efficiency of Tier 1 support